Subindex build by Linnet
http://linnet.126.com  http://blog.csdn.net/redbirdli
火鸟字幕合并器SubindexV0.5
Created time 11.10.31 10:53:15
-=The Last Fantasy=-
翻译:飞跃之星，哈拉尔，龙猫，颀觎，琉琅 校对:岁月倒影，TYY
放我走
Let me go.
你想要我怎么样？
What do you want from me?
说出真相
The truth.
大都会，三年前
-Can I see some ID? -You must be new here.
- 我能看看证件吗？ - 你是新来的吧
没关系，让他进来
Hey, it's okay, let him through.
- 谢谢你，凯瑟 - 不客气
-Thanks, Kasich. -No problem.
- 她很迷人 - 她订婚了
-She's cute. -She's engaged.
觉得怎样？
What do you think?
吵啊
It's loud.
- 今晚有贵宾房间吗？ - 我想我们能准备一间给你
-How's the VIP room tonight? -I think we can make some room for you.
我希望你不必觉得有义务让我开心
I hope you didn't feel obligated to entertain me.
裘德只走了几天
Jude's only gone for a couple days.
我不会觉得这是种义务 你未婚夫是帮了我
I don't believe in obligations. Besides, your fiance did me a favor.
我也不想自己半夜出来玩
I wasn't looking forward to a night out on my own.
直觉告诉我你应该才单身没太久
Something tells me you wouldn't have been alone for very long.
- 两杯苹果马提尼酒 - 马上
-Two apple martinis. -Coming up.
“零后果”
"Zero consequences."
是个挺好的承诺
That's quite a promise.
但要遵守才好
Only if it's kept.
为了我好朋友阿曼达的订婚
To my good friend Amanda on her engagement.
- 干杯 - 干杯
-Cheers. -Cheers.
怎么了？
What is it?
你在干什么？
What are you doing?
- 阿曼达 - 你说你去出差了
-Amanda. -You said you had to go away on business.
听我解释，好吗？等等
I can explain, okay? Just wait.
阿曼达，等下
Amanda, wait a sec--
我可以解释，阿曼达，等等
I can explain, Amanda. Just wait. Amanda!
杂种，你是故意带她来的
You son of a bitch. You did this on purpose.
你自作自受，阿曼达该找个比你好的人
You did it to yourself. Amanda deserves better.
骗子！笔录上是这么写的，但不是事实
Liar! That's what it said in the papers, but that's not what really happened.
- 我说的是实话，看看警方笔录 - 我知道你隐瞒得很全面
-It's the truth. Read the police reports! -I know you covered it up.
虽然我不知道你怎么做到的 但你会付出代价
I don't know how you did it, but you're gonna pay.
你是谁？
Who are you?
不记得了？
Don't you remember?
你杀了我
You killed me.
这次你爸也救不了你了，莱克斯
Daddy can't save you this time, Lex.
片名:超人前传
主题曲《Save me》:谁来拯救我
领衔主演：汤姆・威灵
让你温暖的手伸出驱散我的痛苦
主演:克丽斯汀・克鲁克
谁来拯救我
主演:迈克尔・罗森巴姆
我不在乎你是怎么做到
主演：埃里克・约翰森
只要你留下，和我在一起
主演：山姆・琼斯三世
快来吧，我一直在等待着你
主演：艾利森・麦克
主演：安妮特・奥图尔
约翰・施耐得 饰演 强纳森・肯特
我一直留着整个世界只为你闪耀
超人始创作者:杰瑞・希杰尔和乔・夏斯特
留下，留下
快出现吧
电视策划:阿尔弗雷德・哥夫，麦尔斯・米莱
第十四集:零后果
一周以前
没有什么比奥斯丁先生50分钟 的英语课…
There is nothing like 50 minutes of Mr. Austin's English class...
客串主演:柯林・纳麦克
- …更能激发食欲了 - 没有什么比周一要交的6页学生传记…
-...that works up an appetite. -Nothing like a student biography...
卡梅隆・戴伊
-...due Monday to help me lose mine. -The biography part...
- …更能败掉我的食欲了 - 是因为传记那部分…
…还是因为我们被胡乱分配了啊
...or the fact that our student subjects were randomly assigned?
埃里克・布瑞克
皮特听信说，抽签配对的事被暗中操作过
Pete's convinced that the drawing was fixed.
联合执行制片:格列哥・比曼
There are a dozen ladies in our class, each worthy of lengthy interrogation.
我们班上有那么多女生 个个都值得搞一番详细的调查
- 我偏得和斯坦・吉布森配成一组，调查他吗？ - 那个学生便利店的经理？
-I get stuck with Stan Gibson? -The manager of the student store?
监督制片:马克・伏黑顿
- 我听说他非常… - 高效？
-I hear he's very-- -Efficient?
制片:迈克尔・格林
Very funny. I'm about to learn more about the art of selling "Go Crow" pennants...
搞笑，我正要学习乌鸦队旗的销售艺术…
…简直不是人受的
...than any human should have to endure.
制片:道里斯・伊根
从下课到现在你一直在笑 谁成了你的受害者了？
You haven't stopped smiling since we left. Who's your victim?
正是杰出的肯特先生
The illustrious Mr. Kent himself.
联合制片:格雷格・沃克
-Me? -I take it back.
- 我？ - 我收回你迫害人家的说法
Chloe's the one with the challenge.
克罗伊，你真是个勇于挑战的人
- 什么？ - 我没恶意，克拉克…
-Excuse me? -No offense, Clark...
…不过要想从你身上找出六页有趣的事
...but digging up six pages of interesting on you...
- …得做点严重的发掘工作了 - 我也做过不少事的啊
-...is gonna require serious excavation. -I do stuff.
制片:鲍勃・哈格罗夫
Yes, and I'm sure that once I deploy my journalistic skills on you...
对，只要充分利用了我的新闻调查能力…
…肯定能发掘出你的料的
...l'll unearth a skeleton or two.
克洛伊，这是一个班级作业 不是腐败丑闻调查
You know, Chloe, this is a class project, not a corruption scandal.
联合执行制片:肯・霍顿
别紧张，你本来也没什么要隐瞒吧？
Relax. It's not like you have anything to hide, right?
剧本:马克・伏黑顿
Come on, Clark, cough up. Who'd you get?
克拉克，老实交代，你抽到谁要调查？
不会是拉娜・郎吧
Don't tell me. Lana Lang.
故事:阿尔弗雷德・哥夫，麦尔斯・米莱
瞧他那表情，不用看纸条都知道
Just look at his face, you don't even have to see it.
导演:迈克尔・卡特曼
Like I said, definitely rigged.
正如我所说，肯定有暗中操纵
- 我猜你会赶快动笔了？ - 我能搞好这作业的
-I assume you'll start your paper ASAP? -It's all gonna work out.
我在帮拉娜准备塔龙开张
I'm helping Lana at the Talon getting ready for the opening.
惠特尼忙于他父亲的商店 代理男友当然要顶上了
Surrogate boyfriend does the heavy lifting while Whitney works at his dad's store.
- 说到这个… - 等等
-On that note.... -Wait.
你打算什么时候接受我采访
When are you gonna sit down to do my interview?
好吧，随时
Right. I'll be around.
他在敷衍我吗？
Did he just blow me off?
你进一步，他退两步，别理他了
One step forward, two steps back. Come on.
你答应过一切会按时准备好
You promised everything would be ready on time.
可那时水管还没裂
That was before the plumbing started leaking.
- 太长时间没更换了 - 得花多长时间修理？
-Hasn't been replaced in years. -How long will that take?
不上去检查，没法给你准确答案
I can't really give you a straight answer, not until I crawl up there.
翻新老店，老毛病当然不可避免
You resurrect the past, you get the problems that come with it.
莱克斯・卢瑟马上过来，他需要具体数字…
Lex Luthor's going to be by later. He's going to need numbers...
…施工安排和一个更好的解释
...and a timetable and a better explanation than that.
- 抱歉，我们还没开张 - 我来申请经理助理的职位
-Sorry, we're not open yet. -It's about the assistant manager position.
我来晚了，如果还能领张申请表…
I know I'm late, but if I can get an application....
- 嗯，好，稍等 - 非常感谢，怎么称呼?
-Yeah, yeah, just give me a second. -Great. Really appreciate this, Miss...?
- 郎 - 郎小姐
-Lang. -Lang.
不过，我姨妈要到下周才能给你面试
And just to warn you, my aunt's not taking any more interviews until next week.
没关系，我有的是时间
Well, that's all right. I happen to have all the time in the world.
- 我叫裘德・罗伊斯 - 你好
-I'm Jude Royce. -Hi.
我听说莱克斯・卢瑟在这个项目中有股份
So I understand that Lex Luthor has a stake in this project.
他是业主之一，怎么？你认识他？
Yeah, he's one of the owners. Why? Do you know him?
- 很久以前在大都市的时候 - 一定很有趣
-A lifetime ago in Metropolis. -Must have been interesting.
其实他来斯摩维尔是有原因的
Well, let's just say there's a reason he's in Smallville.
想听我的建议吗？离他远点
You know my advice? Stay away from him.
只要莱克斯插手，事情就会变糟
When Lex gets involved, things usually turn out badly.
你来这干什么？我们之前说好的
What are you doing here? We had an understanding.
那晚之后，我们再也不联系
After that night, we were never to have any contact.
- 我看到他了，莱克斯 - 谁？
-I saw him, Lex. -Who?
裘德
Jude.
- 我们都知道那是不可能的 - 听我说！他还活着
-We both know that's impossible. -Listen to me! He's alive.
我到哪都能看到他
Everywhere I go, I see him.
- 他在跟踪我 - 冷静点，凯瑟
-He's stalking me. -Kasich. Calm down.
我没疯
I'm not crazy.
- 这个人说他要什么了吗？ - 说了，要真相
-This man say what he wanted? -Yeah. The truth.
听着，我在城里有一间公寓
Listen. I keep an apartment in the city.
那很安全，你呆在那，等我电话
It's very secure. You stay there and wait for my call.
- 嘿，莱克斯 - 你好
-Hey, Lex. -Hey.
- 那是谁? - 闲人吧
-Who was that? -Nobody.
听说咱这边漏水了
I hear we sprung a leak.
事情都还顺利吗?
Is everything all right?
- 有点不顺 - 别紧张，漏水而已
-Just a little weirded out. -Relax, it's just a leak.
不是，你一个朋友过来，申请助理的工作
No, a friend of yours came by, applied for the assistant manager position.
他让我离你远点
He told me to stay away from you.
他叫什么
What was his name?
裘德・罗伊斯
Jude Royce.
- 怎么了，莱克斯？ - 他什么时候离开的?
-What is it, Lex? -When did he leave?
就在你进来之前
Just before you came in.
莱克斯，裘德・罗伊斯是谁？
Lex, who's Jude Royce?
相信我，克拉克 虽然我不知道拉娜今天见到的是谁
Trust me, Clark, I have no idea who Lana met today...
但不可能是他
...but it couldn't have been him.
别担心这个，克拉克，我不担心
Don't worry about it, Clark. I'm not.
怎么了？
What's going on?
我不知道
I don't know!
摸摸仪表盘下面
Feel under the dash.
看来有人趁我们进去时搞了点创意啊
Looks like someone decided to get creative while I was inside.
那尖叫声是怎么回事？
What were the screams?
我猜是有人变态的恶作剧
I assume it's someone's twisted idea of a joke.
很成功啊，招来了一堆人
And a successful one. We've managed to draw a crowd.
- 莱克斯 - 克拉克，你真不用担心这事
-Lex. -Clark, this really doesn't concern you.
有人在家吗？
Hello, anybody home?
嘿，我们在做录音访问，儿子
Hey, pull up a microphone, son.
- 克罗伊，怎么了？ - 因为我找不到你…
-Chloe, what's going on? -Since I couldn't find you...
…就决定从故事源头开始我的传记调查
...I decided to start my biographical inquiry at the beginning.
不像我某个所谓的朋友…
Unlike a certain so-called friend of mine...
…你父母很通情达理地接受了我的采访
...your parents gracefully agreed to be interviewed.
克洛伊问了我们一些有趣的问题，克拉克
Chloe's been asking us some very interesting questions, Clark.
谢谢，还有几个问题要探讨，所以…
Thank you. Now, we just have a few more to go, so....
聊聊以前的事吧
We were talking about the early days.
你们是怎么领养克拉克的？
Now, what was involved in adopting Clark?
只是次很普通的领养
Well, it was-- It was just like any normal adoption, I guess.
你能告诉我这个过程吗？ 这个过程花费了几个礼拜还是几个月？
Can you take me through the process? Did it takes weeks or months?
你们用了律师，还是通过代理人…?
Did you guys use a lawyer, or did you go through an agen--?
该死，录音带用完了 没关系，我车上还有几盘
Shoot. I'm out of tape. That's okay, I've got some extra C-90s in my car.
我很快回来
I'll be right back.
克洛伊为了学校作业，在调查你的生活吗？
Chloe's researching your life for a school project?
- 什么时候的事？ - 我们今天分的作业
-When did that happen? -We just got the assignment today.
没想到她真会像迈克・华莱士一样较真
I didn't know she was gonna go Mike Wallace.
儿子，我们不介意谈论你…
We don't mind talking about you...
…可她要是再问关于领养的事…
...but if she starts asking questions about the adoption....
领养怎么了？
What about the adoption?
有什么我应该知道的事？
Is there something I should know?
当然，我们需要编个故事…
Well, of course, we had to make up a story...
…但这更复杂
...but it's more complicated than that.
就说我们不想任何人调查这方面好了
Let's just say it's a subject we would rather not have anyone explore.
不好意思，打扰到你们了吗？
Sorry. Am I interrupting?
克拉克，既然你终于走进我的调查圈子…
Clark, now that you're finally spinning in my orbit...
…我也有些事想问你
...I have a couple of pertinents for you too.
实际上，我只是过来看一下
Actually, this is just a pit stop for me.
我正要去找拉娜准备我的论文
I'm on my way to meet Lana to work on my paper.
克拉克，不是我有意瞎猜，但你是在回避我吗？
You know, Clark, not to strike a paranoid note, but are you avoiding me?
明天，我保证
Tomorrow, I promise.
好的，这不是一个正式问题…
Okay, this isn't an official question...
…我也不想你们误会我这问题…
...and I don't want you guys to take it the wrong way...
…不过，你们的儿子一直这么奇怪吗？
...but has your son always been this strange?
- 感觉怎么样？ - 什么感觉？
-How does it feel? -Feel?
单枪匹马就把差点变成停车场的塔龙救回来？
To single-handedly bring the Talon back from the brink of becoming a parking garage?
这种被依靠，肩负责任的感觉很好
It's nice, you know, being counted on, having responsibility.
- 人们对我也会不一样了 - 这下不会觉得你是脆弱的人了
-People treat you differently. -Like you won't break.
终于感觉自己慢慢脱下了公主的外衣
Finally feel like I'm shedding that fairy-princess costume.
- 莱克斯，你来干嘛? - 承包商打电话给我
-Lex, what are you doing here? -Contractor called.
说他有了估价，希望我来这找他
Said he had an estimate, wanted me to meet him here.
怎么了？
What the hell?
你还好吗？
Are you okay?
我从后门进来时，有人扑过来…
Yeah. I came in the back door and some guy jumped me...
…逼我给他开门，还打了我的头
...and forced me to let him in and bashed me over the head.
你看见他的脸没?
Did you see his face?
没有
No.
看
Look.
我锁门的时候它不在那，我去叫警察
That wasn't there when I locked up. I'll go call the police.
莱克斯，上面有你的名字
Lex, your name's on it.
写的是“零后果”
Zero consequences.
你怎么样了？
How you holding up?
本来还好…可一看到那手
I was fine...until it showed up.
是的，问得真愚蠢
Yeah, stupid question.
怎么会有这么变态的人做这种事？
What kind of a sick person would do a thing like that?
我不知道
I don't know.
从没见过莱克斯这么不安
But I've never seen Lex so freaked out before.
我也没
Join the club.
那人警告我，凡是莱克斯插手的事都没好下场
That guy warned me. He said everything Lex touches ends badly.
关于他和他的过去，我们到底知道多少?
How much do we really know about him and his past?
我希望你们知道我对此多么抱歉
I want you both to know how truly sorry I am about this.
我保证不会影响开张
I promise this won't affect the grand opening.
可我们会在开张前就已经声名狼藉了
We're going to be infamous before we even open the doors.
你知道他是谁吗？盒子里那手的…
Do you know who he is? The guy in the.... You know.
马克斯・凯瑟，多年前我们在大都会相识
Max Kasich. And yes, I knew him a long time ago in Metropolis.
你知道谁可能对他做那种事吗？
Do you have any idea who might have done this to him?
不知道
Not at all.
会是你的老朋友裘德・罗伊斯吗？
What about your old friend Jude Royce?
- 我相信不是他，克拉克 - 为什么？
-I doubt it could have been him, Clark. -Why?
因为他已经死了三年了
Because he's been dead for three years.
我从肯特家得到的唯一…
The only information I got from the Kents...
…惊天动地的消息就是克拉克不喜欢豌豆
...was the earth-shattering admission that Clark hates peas.
塔龙出现了断肢，但你所谈论的只有克拉克？
A body part shows up at the Talon and all you can talk about is Clark?
你分不出轻重吗？莱克斯・卢瑟肯定与其有关
Where are your priorities? Lex Luthor must be mixed up in this.
- 别这样，我知道你对卢瑟有意见 - 岂止是意见
-I know you've got issues with the Luthors-- -More than issues.
你知道卢瑟家族是怎么对我家人的
You know what they did to my family.
这些信息也要一条一条来谈
One piece of investigative information at a time.
- 现在，关于克拉克… - 克洛伊，你想从我这里知道什么？
-Now, about Clark.... -Chloe, what do you want from me?
如果把别人都比作高级矿泉水 克拉克也是像自来水一样普通
In a world of designer water, Clark's from the tap.
我知道，但你认识他最长时间 我所要的不过是一点趣闻轶事罢了…
I know, but you've known him the longest. All I need is just a little anecdote...
…只要一点关于他灰暗过去的消息
...just a small piece of information from Clark's deep, dark past.
一年级时发生了件事
Well, there was something back in the first grade.
谢谢！这可比我这两天得到的信息还要多
Thank you! That's more than I've uncovered the past two days.
现在，拜托，快给我讲吧
Now, please, let's continue.
当时有个大我们三级的小霸王
There was a bully three grades ahead.
这家伙要把学校里每个人都揍一顿
This dude was determined to pound dents into every kid.
那天轮到我倒霉，他正要揍我…
One day it was my turn. He was just about to take my head off...
- …克拉克就跳到我们中间 - 克拉克竟然干涉打架
-...when Clark jumped between us. -So Clark ran interference?
不过，这听起来没什么特别，皮特…
Now, as kind as that sounds, Pete...
…我不认为它符合“惊人猛料”的标准
...I don't think it falls into the "something amazing" test.
- 什么标准？ - 我还没说完
-What test? -I'm not finished.
克拉克不只是推了他，连门都撞破了
Clark didn't just push Braindead, he put him through a door...
…当时遍地碎片，合叶都断了 我至今不知道他是怎么做到的
...as in splinters and broken hinges. How he did it, I still have no idea.
- 那家伙个头至少是我们两倍 - 克拉克 ，怎么解释？
-Guy was at least twice our size. -Clark, any comments?
我们那时才六岁，两倍也只不过三英尺高
Well, we were, you know, 6 years old. Twice our size was three feet tall.
如果想听更多以前的轶事 还是问本人吧
If you need more ancient history, ask the source.
我在学生商店还约了人
I've got an appointment at the student store.
祝你调查愉快
Have fun.
如此，克拉克・肯特的秘密更神秘了
And so the mystery that isn't Clark Kent deepens.
- 秘密？ - 对
-Mystery? -Yeah.
因为你总是扮演着妨碍者的角色…
Since you continue to play obstructionist...
…我已经从其他途径找到了消息
...l've had to find information through other means.
我发现你的领养手续 是在大都会的联合慈善机构完成的
I found that your adoption was done through Metropolis United Charities...
…奇怪的地方就在这，他们那时才成立了六个月…
...but this is the strange part. They were in business for six months...
…而且，你是他们唯一的领养案例
...and from what I can tell, yours is the only adoption they handled.
不敢相信你调查这些，克洛伊
I can't believe you did this, Chloe.
你不知道吗？我以为你父母告诉你了
You didn't know? I just assumed that your parents would have told you.
- 我是说，你不感兴趣吗？ - 我为什么要感兴趣？
-I mean, weren't you interested? -Why would I be?
我亲生父母要么过世了要么抛弃了我
My biological parents are either dead or didn't want me.
- 而你正在窥探我的私人生活 - 我只是想彻底搞明白而已
-You're prying into my private life. -I was just trying to be thorough.
不过是一个班级作业 我昨天只花了一小时和拉娜在一起，就这样
This is a class project. I spent an hour yesterday with Lana, that's it.
我需要点小资料就成了 你非把我当成要调查的秘密吗
That's all I needed. I'm not some mystery for you to solve.
克拉克，我…
Clark, I....
说吧，瑞恩斯先生
Talk to me, Mr. Raines.
据门卫说，凯瑟没能赶到你在大都会的公寓
According to the doorman, Kasich never made it to the apartment in Metropolis.
- 罗伊斯呢？ - 他父母在他小时候就过世了
-What about Royce? -His parents died when he was young.
因为车祸，他是独子，继承了所有东西
Car accident. He was an only child, inherited everything.
阿曼达・罗斯曼呢？你跟踪到她了吗？
And Amanda Rothman? Have you tracked her down yet?
她搬走了，没留下地址 你最后一次和她通话是什么时候？
She moved, left no forwarding address. When's the last time you spoke to her?
- 大约三年前 - 我会更深入调查，但需要些时间
-About three years ago. -I'll go wider, but it could take some time.
如果能告诉我发生了什么，或许会有帮助
It'd help if you tell me what's going on.
不，我不能跟你说，你只是安保负责人
No, it wouldn't. You're my head of security.
你找到并警告她可能会有危险
You find her and warn her she could be in danger.
这就是全部你需要知道的
That's all you need to know.
让一下，警察 借过，警察
Make a path. Police. Excuse me, excuse me. Police.
- 你是谁？ - 大都会警察局，警探萨姆・费伦
-Who are you? -Detective Sam Phelan, Metropolis P.D.
你是这破动物园的保安吗？
Are you what passes for security in this zoo?
- 对 - 呆在这，我们得谈谈
-Yeah. -Don't go anywhere. We'll talk.
- 感谢上帝，你来了 - 莱克斯啊，莱克斯啊
-Thank God you're here. -Lex, Lex.
你这回真把事搞大了
You really put your foot in it this time.
告诉我到底发生了什么？
Tell me exactly what happened.
如果你不信任我，我可帮不了你
Hey, if you fall apart on me, I can't help you.
到底发生什么了？
Now what went down?
这是事实？
That's exactly what happened?
好，接下来这样
Good. Here's how it's gonna go.
你从没来过这里，你的名字… …不会出现在任何报纸或者警察笔录里
You were never here. Your name will not appear in any papers or the police report.
- 怎么会？ - 这就是你老爸钱的作用
-How? -That's what your daddy's money's for.
这次他要花大价钱了
This one's gonna cost him.
- 阿曼达怎么办？ - 我会安排好每个人的口供
-What about Amanda? -I'll take care of everybody's story...
…但你永远不能再见她 或者再跟她联系，明白吗？
...but you are never to see her or talk to her again. You got it?
给这家伙打电话，他会帮你处理肩伤
Call this guy, he'll take care of your shoulder.
不要去医院
No emergency rooms.
好，出去吧
All right, get out of here.
- 你看到事情经过了？ - 大部分
-Did you see what happened? -Most of it.
高兴点，你因此会得到一大笔钱
Well, smile. Because you're about to come into some serious money.
就没什么要说的吗？
Nothing to say?
- 我以为莱克斯・卢瑟无所不知呢 - 听着，你个变态，杂种
-I thought Lex Luthor had all the answers. -Look, you twisted son of a bitch.
- 我不知道你想要什么 - 我想知道在零点俱乐部发生了什么
-I don't know what you want. -I wanna know what happened at Club Zero.
被掩盖的事实
The cover-up.
你知道那个警察吗？
You know the cop?
笔录提到的那个人，费伦？
The one on the report? Phelan?
他死了
He's dead.
似乎你也多少有牵连，太有趣了
It seems that you were somehow involved in that too. I find that very interesting.
你为什么不现在就杀了我？
Why don't you kill me now?
因为看你受折磨更有趣
Because it's more fun to watch you suffer.
看你害怕自己任何时刻都可能会被，砰！
Knowing that at any moment, bang!
告诉我！
Tell me.
到底发生了什么？
What really happened?
莱克斯！
Lex!
莱克斯，你还好吧？
Lex, you all right?
克拉克，你来这干嘛？
Clark, what are you doing here?
你办公室的人告诉我你在这
Your office told me you were here.
我好像听到有其他人在这
I thought I heard someone else.
不，就我一个人
No. I'm all by myself.
嘿，我调查了马克斯・凯瑟
Hey, I looked up Max Kasich.
我知道零点俱乐部发生了什么
I know what happened at Club Zero.
他开枪杀了裘德・罗伊斯 除了你，所有人都被牵扯进来了
That he was shot and killed Jude Royce. Everyone fits into this except for you.
- 怎么了？ - 拜托了，克拉克
-What's going on? -Please, Clark.
为了我们的友谊，拜托你别插手这事
For our friendship, I'm asking you to stay out of this.
一些秘密最好还是不管为妙
Some secrets are better left alone.
克拉克
Clark.
拜托，儿子，牛可不会自己喂自己
Come on, son, the cows aren't gonna feed themselves.
- 你昨晚很晚才睡？ - 我在帮拉娜
-You have a late night? -I was helping Lana.
她不想让断肢事件影响塔龙开业
She's not gonna let the whole body-part incident delay the opening of the Talon.
这就是跟莱克斯・卢瑟这种人打交道的结果
That's what happens when you get into business with somebody like Lex Luthor.
如果不是莱克斯，塔龙就变成停车场了
If it wasn't for Lex, the Talon would be a parking garage.
孩子，真不知他对你的影响会多远
Son, he casts a very, very long shadow.
我只是想保证你们这些孩子不会受伤
I just want to make sure none of you kids get hurt, that's all.
过去的已经过去了，我们最好向前看
The past is in the past. The best we can do is look to the future.
好吧，你说倒我了
All right, you got me.
说到这，克罗伊的论文怎么样了？
Speaking of that, how's Chloe's paper coming along?
- 我想她的采访应该结束了吧 - 不确定
-I assume she's done with her interviews? -I'm not sure.
听我说，克拉克 如果她跟你提及豌豆的事情，我很抱歉
Look, Clark, if she mentions anything to you about the peas, I'm sorry.
这是我当时能想到的第一件事
It's the first thing that came to mind.
如果她跟我提及了大都会慈善联合会呢？
And if she mentions anything to me about the Metropolis United Charities?
我本以为坚持不懈是一种可贵的品质 可她这样真是…
I used to think perseverance was an admirable quality.
自从知道真相，我还没想过领养的事
Since I learned the real truth, I hadn't thought about the adoption.
爸爸，克罗伊告诉我 你们领养我的机构只成立了六个月
Dad, Chloe told me the agency you used was only open six months...
…而我是唯一一个被领养的孩子
...and I was the only kid adopted.
听我说，孩子…
Look, son...
…即使通过正常渠道领养个孩子 过程都很艰辛的
...the process is a really tough one even when you go through normal channels.
领养你，只是更复杂点罢了，就是这样
With you, it was just a little more complicated, that's all.
- 都合法吗？ - 都合法，只是…
-Is everything legal? -Yeah, it's legal, it's just....
当时要办妥这件事 不是我跟你妈能力所及的
Well, it required a higher level of access than your mother or I had.
什么意思？
What does that mean?
我只想跟你说 在地窖里的那个东西和你的出生证明之间…
Let's just say it's a long road between what's sitting in our storm cellar...
…有太复杂的故事
...and what's written on your birth certificate.
- 你听到了吗？ - 听到什么？
-You hear that? -Hear what?
牛群在那边高地，应该能听到动静才对
The whole herd's just over that rise. We ought to be hearing something.
你觉得发生了什么事？
What do you think happened?
为什么卢瑟集团会把废物倒弃这儿？
Why would LuthorCorp dump their stuff here?
我去从别的角度拍些照片
I'm gonna go take from some different angles.
肯特夫妇，我不清楚怎么会这样…
Mr. and Mrs. Kent, I have no idea how this could have happened...
…但我会尽全力找到原因
...but I'll do everything in my power to find out.
我当然也会补偿你的家畜损失
And I'll pay for your livestock, of course.
这就是你解决所有问题的方式吗，莱克斯？
You think that's how you solve everything, don't you, Lex?
撒点钱，就希望问题能消失
You sprinkle a little money on it and hope the problem goes away.
事实上，有些事情可不是那么好办的
Well, obviously, some things are a little more difficult than that.
我还以为我在你父亲心里的形象 不会更差了呢
I didn't think it was possible to fall any further in your father's eyes.
显然，我错了
Obviously, I was wrong.
但我从没放任让这样的事情发生
I'd never intentionally allow something like this to happen.
这跟零点俱乐部有关吗？
Does this have anything to do with Club Zero?
- 我觉得是 - 你得告诉警方…
-I think so. -You need to tell the authorities...
…所有你知道的事情 现在这不只是你个人的事了
...everything you know. This isn't just about you anymore.
卢瑟先生，环保局的人找你谈话，在那边
Mr. Luthor, the C.E.P. guy needs to talk to you. He's over there.
看来你们公司的环境记录要有污点了
Looks like a black mark on your company's environmental record.
- 我要去找治安官 - 跟他说什么？
-I'm gonna walk over and get the sheriff. -And tell him what?
告诉他克拉克・肯特来过电话，谢谢
Just tell him that Clark Kent called. Thank you.
- 打给谁? - 我在找莱克斯
-Who was that? -I'm trying to reach Lex.
他不在公司也不在家…
He's not in the office. He's not at the mansion...
…手机也直接转到语音信箱
...and his cell phone goes straight to voice mail.
- 爸爸在哪？ - 还在监督搬运死牛
-Where's Dad? -Still supervising the removal of the cows.
- 莱克斯说他会赔款的 - 克拉克，这不仅仅是钱的事
-Lex said he'd pay for that. -Clark, this isn't just about money.
谁也不知道这会对我们和邻居的健康 造成什么样的威胁
We don't know what kind of health threat this poses to us or to our neighbors.
我想这不是莱克斯的错
I don't think this is Lex's fault.
我想有人在陷害他，因为夜店的事
I think someone is trying to set him up because of what happened at the nightclub.
看
Look.
零点俱乐部死亡事件
- 事情还不明朗之前，我不想… - 莱克斯一直是个很好的朋友
-Until this is cleared up, I don't-- -Lex has always been a good friend.
我知道，我也一直维护他…
I know. I'm usually the one who defends him...
…但他过去的名声确实不好
...but there are some things in his past that are a little shady.
我以为咱们家不以过去评价人呢
In this family we don't look at the past.
克拉克，我在大都会长大 我了解卢瑟家族
Clark, I grew up in Metropolis, I know the Luthor world.
看上去诱惑又有趣，但他们的孩子都太早熟…
It looks glamorous and fun, but the kids grow up too fast...
…很容易陷入麻烦
...and they can get into trouble.
莱克斯的事情已经开始影响你了
Whatever's happening to Lex is starting to affect you.
盒子里的断肢和中毒的奶牛？ 这些都不正常
Body parts in boxes and poisoned cows? This isn't normal.
你想让我怎么做？跟他断绝关系？
What do you want me to do? Cut him out of my life?
不，我希望你暂时冷下这段友情 直到我们清楚到底发生了什么
No, I want you to cool it off for a while until we know what really happened.
我和你爸爸不想你被他的问题牵连
Your father and I just don't want to see you pulled into his problems.
我能跟你谈谈吗？
Can I talk to you for a second?
你好吗？
How you doing?
- 那要看你要不要录音了 - 好吧，我道歉
-That depends if it's on the record or not. -Okay, I deserve that.
我并没想拿领养机构的事来套你的话
Look, I didn't mean to ambush you with the whole adoption agency thing.
你看到有故事，就去调查
Hey, you saw a story and you went right for it.
- 记者就这么做的 - 你是对的
-That's what journalists do. -You're right.
我没想到这会伤害到你
I didn't think about how it would hurt you.
你知道，虽然记者的本性有些反叛
And, you know, as much as journalistic instinct rebels...
…但我不想因为一个课题失去朋友
...l'd rather have a friend than a subject...
…所以我不再调查了
...so I'm dropping the whole thing.
谢谢
Thank you.
我能问个问题吗？
Can I ask you a question?
绝对没有录音
Totally off the record.
你想知道自己的亲生父母吗？
Do you ever wonder about your biological parents?
生命里的每一天都在想
Every day of my life.
看来我不是唯一做调查的人
Looks like I'm not the only one doing some digging.
- 零点俱乐部怎么了？ - 跟莱克斯的过去有关
-What's Club Zero? -Part of Lex's past...
…他让我不要管
...he asked me to stay out of.
我刚好给你父母带了些照片来
By the way, I brought by some pictures for your parents.
申请保险赔偿的时候可能用的上
I figured they could use it for insurance purposes and stuff.
我得走了
I'll see you later. I gotta go.
克罗伊…
Chloe...
…是同一个人
...it's the same guy.
- 可是他不是已经… - 死了
-Wait, but he's-- -Dead.
救命!
Help!
有人吗？
Somebody!
救命！
Help!
有人吗？
Somebody!
没有莱克斯的回话 早上到现在都没人联系得上他
No word from Lex. No one's spoken to him since this morning.
我调出了这个所谓的死人的驾照 是用约翰・史密斯这个名字登记的，是原件
I pulled our alleged dead guy's license. It's registered to a John Smith. Original.
他在大都会有个地址 但不是在环保局工作的
He has an address in Metropolis and does not work for the C.E.P.
- 你怎么做到的？ - 我黑进了车辆管理局的数据库
-How'd you do that? -I hacked into the DMV database.
- 有时候坚持不懈依然是个优点吧 - 打电话给大都会警察局
-Sometimes persistence is a good thing. -Call Metropolis P.D.
- 让他们去那个地址 - 发生了什么？
-Have them go to that address. -What's going on?
我想莱克斯有大麻烦了
I think Lex is in serious trouble.
准备要说了吗？
You ready to talk?
你终于到了三年前就应该在的地方
You're finally where you should have been three years ago.
暴露在聚光灯下
Exposed in the spotlight.
你想要我怎么样？
What do you want from me?
说出零点俱乐部里的真相
The truth about Club Zero.
大都会警局车
凯瑟
Kasich.
打扰了，请问里面还有别人吗？
Excuse me, did you find anyone else in there?
- 你知道零点俱乐部在哪吗？ - 孩子，你问晚了六个月了
-Do you know where I can find Club Zero? -You're six months too late, kid.
- 什么意思？ - 已经关门了
-What do you mean? -Well, it closed down.
就是第78道和主干道路口的一间旧仓库
It was an old warehouse on 78th and Main.
骗子！那只是报道上说的，但不是真相
Liar! That's what it said in the papers, but that's not what really happened.
- 事实就是这样，看警察笔录去吧！ - 我知道你掩盖得很全面
-It's the truth. Read the police reports! -I know you covered it up.
虽然我不知道你怎么做到的 但你要为此付出代价
I don't know how you did it, but you're gonna pay.
你是谁？
Who are you?
不记得了吗？
Don't you remember?
你杀了我
You killed me.
这次你爸也救不了你，莱克斯
Daddy can't save you this time, Lex.
游戏结束了，莱克斯
No more games, Lex.
真相大白的时间到了
It's time for the truth.
我认得你，你是塔龙的建筑承保人
I know you. You're the contractor from the Talon.
那是我白天的工作
That's my day job.
你是谁？
Who are you?
阿曼达从没和你谈过她的家人吗？
Amanda never talked about her family?
她说过她有个哥哥，在中央城
She said she had a brother in Central City.
他在监狱里 阿曼达是唯一和他联系的人
He was in prison. She was the only person who kept in touch.
在监狱里时，我就视她为我的生命
She was my lifeline when I was inside.
可惜我没有个能把我从监狱里弄出来的富老爸
I never had a rich daddy to keep me out of jail.
- 我不明白，你想要什么？ - 我要什么？我要什么？
-I don't understand. What do you want? -What do I want? What do I want?
我要帮我妹妹复仇
I want vengeance for my sister.
什么意思？阿曼达在哪？
What do you mean? Where's Amanda?
她死了，莱克斯
She's dead, Lex.
她一年前自杀了
She committed suicide a year ago.
- 我没听说 - 那是因为你对她不管不顾
-I never knew. -That's because you cut her out of your life.
零点俱乐部那事之后，她完全变了 裘德的死毁了她
She was never the same after Club Zero. Jude's death devastated her.
他是她生命中挚爱，你夺走了他
He was the love of her life. You took all that away.
她失去了活下去的希望
She had nothing to live for.
那是谁？
Who's that?
意外的好运
Lucky break.
阿曼达葬礼后几星期 我去布鲁德海文市的一家小餐馆
Couple weeks after Amanda's funeral, I walk into a greasy spoon in Bludhaven...
在那碰到他，我都不敢相信 一个做汉堡的快餐厨师
...and there he is. I couldn't believe it. Short-order cook flipping burgers.
你听过“现实中会有另一个自己”的说法吗？ 连我都得仔细看看
You know how they say everyone in life has a double? I had to look twice.
我在想，如果他能骗到我，也能骗到你
I figure if he can fool me, he can fool you.
他为什么要这么做？
Why'd he do it?
他在保释中，需要钱，我就有了这个想法
He was on parole, needed the money, and that's when I got the idea.
你毁了我妹妹曼蒂的生活 我也要毁了你的
You ruined Mandy's life, I'd ruin yours.
曼蒂终于能得到她应得的公正了
Mandy's finally gonna get the justice she deserves.
你说对了，没错
You were right.
报纸，警方笔录，和我对费伦所说的
You were right. The newspapers, the police reports, what I told Phelan.
全是假的，你想要真相？我告诉你
They were all lies. You want the truth? I'll give it to you.
- 不，你又在扭曲事实！ - 这就是真正发生的事！
-No, no, no. You're twisting it again! -That's what happened!
这就是事实，阿曼达扣动了扳机
That's what happened. Amanda pulled the trigger.
她杀了裘德 我隐瞒这一切都是为了保护她
She shot Jude. I was just trying to protect her.
我受够你了，莱克斯！
I'm through with you, Lex!
杀了我，阿曼达也不会回来了
Killing me won't bring Amanda back.
- 这一切都改变不了发生过的事 - 我不管
-None of this can change what happened. -I don't care.
今晚之后，你不会再伤害任何人了
After tonight, you'll never hurt anyone else.
你逃不了过去的，莱克斯
You can't escape your past, Lex.
莱克斯！
Lex!
趴下！楼上有人有枪
Get down! There's a man with a gun up there.
哪里？你是说他？
Where? You mean that guy?
- 发生了什么？ - 我不知道
-What happened? -I have no idea.
你怎么找到我的？
How'd you find me here?
靠我朋友的一点帮助
With a little help from my friends.
- 你觉得怎么样？ - 我很惊讶
-So, what do you think? -I'm definitely surprised.
我也是
Me too.
克罗伊在哪？
Where's Chloe?
她说要像明星一样，晚到一点
She said she wanted to be fashionably late.
这个送给你
I got this for you.
别担心，不是断肢
Don't worry, it's not a body part.
在阁楼上找到的，是我爷爷的
It was in the attic. It was my grandfather's.
塔龙当年刚开张时照的
It was taken just after the Talon opened.
- 你可以把它挂在柜台上 - 克拉克，太惊喜了，谢谢
-Figured you could hang it above the counter. -Clark, it's amazing. Thank you.
不用谢
You're welcome.
我要回去做事了
I better get back to work.
感觉怎么样？
How does it feel?
- 有点怕，不要告诉别人 - 我会为你保守秘密的
-Terrifying. Don't tell anybody. -Your secret's safe with me.
我感觉你在躲我，克拉克
I get the feeling you're avoiding me, Clark.
我发现自己对你很不了解
I just realized there's a lot I don't know about you.
怕我不光彩的过去会影响你？
You think my dark past is gonna rub off on you?
我撒谎说自己开的枪 是为了保护阿曼达
I was trying to protect Amanda.
我爸爸根本不会去帮她…
My father wouldn't raise a finger to help her...
…但我知道他肯定会尽量保护他独子的
...but I knew he'd do anything to save his only son.
所以你代人受罪，才掩盖了真相？
So you took the fall and everything was covered up?
这是真正发生的事吗？这是真相吗？
Is that really what happened? Is it the truth?
真相就是，我会尽我所能去保护我的朋友
The truth is, I'd do anything to protect my friends.
大都会联合慈善机构